

# MARTINEJA S. COATS

# **CUSTOMER SUCCESS MANAGER**

# CONTACT

216.543.7586

Martinejacoats@gmail.com

6224 S Greenwood Ave #2 Chicago, IL 60637

# **EDUCATION**

#### **MASTER OF SCIENCE**

Information Technology Loyola University Chicago Completion December 2024

# **CERTIFICATION**

Computer Science Loyola University December 2022

# CERTIFICATION

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Microsoft AZ – 900 October 2023

#### CERTIFICATION

Google Data Analytics Coursera August 2022

#### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Project Management
- · Results Oriented Thinker
- Exceptional Team Collaboration
- Enterprise Account Management
- International Business Relations
- Resource Delegation
- Exceptional Presentation Skills
- Data Analytics
- Problem Resolution

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Accomplished business and analytics professional with over 13 years of exceptional performance in account management, operational oversight, strategy development, success planning and software expertise. Seeking to utilize an established record of success to propel teams, optimize workflows, and spearhead initiatives while exceeding objectives through measurable results.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CUSTOMER SUCCESS MANAGER**

Dataiku / Chicago, IL / January 2022 - Present

Actively manage a portfolio of 30+ accounts as a trusted advisor and strategic partner helping customers unlock the potential of their data. Assist customers in the development of business use cases that deliver organizational value and data science solutions while strengthening customer relationships. Partner with Implementation Managers, Engineers, Sales, Partners, and Data Scientists to ensure successful enablement of Dataiku Software throughout various stages of the customer journey.

- Leverage customer analytics methodologies, data, and strategic KPI's to drive adoption, identify customer expansion opportunities, prevent churn, upskill end users, and ensure customer ROI.
- Provide guidance and success planning to support successful implementation of projects from design to production while addressing adhoc needs related to integration, machine learning, artificial intelligence, architecture, and data science capabilities within Dataiku.
- Ensured 25% upsell, 15% decrease in churn, and 90% retention by spearheading improved processes and Customer Success standardization strategies that ensure consistent value delivery.

#### **CUSTOMER SUCCESS MANAGER**

CCC Information Services / Chicago, IL / January 2017 – January 2022

Responsible for maintaining customer relationships side by side various Account Teams, Implementation Teams, Product Management, and Technical Teams. Responsible for in-depth industry analysis and data insights throughout the customer journey. Worked to develop and execute customized strategies that improve customer performance while implementing success plans for both short and long-term business objectives.

- Manage multiple account workflow rules, SaaS products, and guidelines.
- Responsible for design, development, and delivery of in-person and virtual software demonstration to increase product adoption and upsells.
- Build and maintain custom Power BI, Salesforce, MicroStrategy, and Tableau reports/dashboards allowing on-demand data access.
- Achieved 2x Spot Award for above and beyond contribution directly impacting growth, sales, and customer relationships among Enterprise Accounts.
- Served as a mentor to Customer Success Managers throughout onboarding.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- SaaS Implementation
- Web Services
- Microsoft Office
- Productivity Analysis
- CRM Reporting
- Process Improvement

# PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

- Association for Talent Development (ATD)
- Cleveland State University
  Alumni Association

#### **INTERESTS**

- · Community Service
- Creative Writing
- Theatre
- Traveling

# **EXPERIENCE** continued

#### **AREA MANAGER**

Verizon Wireless / Chicago, IL / March 2016 - January 2017

Responsible for staffing, operations, affiliate partnerships, budget, sales trends, and all aspects of business while effectively managing area staff. Other duties including but not limited to; inventory management and marketing while exceeding weekly, monthly, and quarterly KPI's. Consistently recognized as a Top-Performing territory manager performing above standard and exceeding targets.

- Decreased inventory losses by %21 while increasing sales by %28.
- Stabilized staff turnover through strategic training and sales development.
- Trained all staff including single store managers and assistant managers to uphold excellence through improved sales strategies, and team building.

#### PROCUREMENT SUPERVISOR

Vox Mobile / Independence, Oh / April 2015 - March 2016

Worked with both U.S and international clients to determine cost effective and efficient procurement needs while managing staff. Utilized workflow strategies to oversee purchase details, negotiate carrier terms, and execute orders while maintaining client and carrier relationships.

- · Maintain vendor and client accounts.
- Provide reporting data while maintaining dashboards through ServiceNow and Tableau.
- Implemented and coordinated new procurement processes that lead to reduced client escalations by %14 annually.

#### TRAINING FACILITATOR

Progressive Insurance / Mayfield Heights, Oh / December 2013 - May 2015

Manage training of onboarding customer service department new hires. Responsible for maintenance of the Learning Management System materials. Facilitate and deliver training plan to prepare new hires adequately for success in upcoming role. Served as training lead for continuous development and received recognition for decreased turnover of graduating new hires.

- Coordinate all logistics for training sessions.
- Provide support to cross functional teams via email communication, meeting coordination, reporting, and other functions.
- Continually evaluate procedures to monitor and analyze training effectiveness and update curriculum as needed.

#### **AREA MANAGER**

General Nutrition Center / Richmond, Oh / April 2008 - December 2013

Responsible for staffing, operations, affiliate partnerships, budget, sales trends, and all aspects of business while efficiently managing associates, store managers, and keyholders. Other duties including but not limited to, shipping, receiving, inventory management, and marketing while exceeding weekly, monthly, and quarterly KPI's. Consistently recognized for top regional performance.

- Build successful regional teams through strategic employee development.
- Create reflective reports of both positive and negative sales trends as well as customer experience.
- Increased annual sales by %23.